JON SCHINELLA

Negaunee, MI, 49866 | 517-960-4241 | jonschinella@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

With over 8 years of experience in the electronics/controls field I am extremely excited to continue my career path with software development. I have an extensive background in electronics, team-leading and diagnostic skills that I am sure will be utilized within my new field.

TECHNICAL & INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, Markdown

Libraries and Frameworks: Tailwind, Express, Mongoose. Node, React, Django, Axios.

Databases and other: Mongo DB, Neon, GitHub, Heroku, Postgres.

Interpersonal skills: Team Leadership, Organization, Communication skills with emphasis on client

communication.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Capstone- GitHub - Heroku | | html | css | javascript | express | node | mongoose | mongodb | react This project is a display of how much I can learn. Being the last project of my college I developed site with calendar scheduling, embedded spotify music and user authentication.

- MERN MERN stack structure was incorporated into this project with frontend and backend operations clearly separated into folder structures.
- Spotify Web API Log in and play some music! This was a very technical challenge but i was able to accomplish this and the PKCE verification process.
- JWT- For the normal site log in dove into the JWT token authorization
- Calendar Scheduler This is a java based program which shows my skills in data manipulation and processing with mongoDB

Pitcru- GitHub - Heroku | html | css | python | bs4 | django

This was a group project, my responsibilities were to manage all database connections, apis, schemas, etc

- APIs In this application I got to dive into making API calls using API ninjas car database
- BS4 I incorporated Beautiful Soup to access images rendered from a google search.
- User Authentication I was on the forefront for developing the user authentication in the Django framework and extending a model onto the Django user model.
- Model Relationship All the models and relationships were my responsibility during development

Fish Reporter - GitHub | html | css | javascript | express | node | mongoose | mongodb

Poseidons Index purpose is to allow users to find local fishing locations, leave comments, see types of fish, etc..

- Structure- This site is a great display of utilizing a MEN stack structure.
- Database- Using MongoDB I am seeding and manipulated date with express and axios.
- Styling Challenged myself to create a vanilla CSS and still incorporate full responsiveness.
- Model Relationship All the models and relationships were my responsibility during development

Portfolio - GitHub | html | css | javascript | Markdown

Check out my full bio website! Maybe play a game of hang-man or just learn a little more about me.

- Navigation & Display I learned a lot about typical CSS formatting (Grid / Flex)
- Game Project Great display of my experience with DOM and Javascript

EXPERIENCE

Nagel, Controls Engineer

Ann Arbor, MI, 2015 – 2023

- Developed and installed Industrial machines, leveraging skills in programming with RSlogix 5000,
 TIA portal, and Simatic S7. Worked closely with customers and other team members during installs and development.
- Collaborated closely with customers and team members during installs and development, showcasing strong teamwork and communication skills.
- Integrated IoT devices into control systems, demonstrating adaptability to emerging technologies.

Potlatch Lumber, Electrical Technician

Gwinn, MI, 2014 – 2015

- Led electrical diagnostics, showcasing troubleshooting skills and proficiency in programming RSlogix 500, 5000, and Modicon.
- Implemented preventive maintenance strategies, enhancing system reliability and minimizing downtime.

Northern Michigan University, ET420 Tutor

Marquette, MI, 2013 – 2013

- Provided afterhours support for C programming, showcasing teaching and mentoring abilities.
- Programmed with microchip 16f and 18f series
- Developed logic for Arduino applications, demonstrating a strong foundation in embedded systems

EDUCATION

General Assembly Remote, Certificate Expected: 03/2024

Full-stack software engineering 420+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies.

Northern Michigan University, Electronics Engineering Technology *Marquette, Michigan, Graduated: 01/2014*

Electrical Engineering 4 year program focused on the theoretical formulas and overall design of electrical circuitry. Excelled in micro chip programming using 16f and 18f series microchips and Arduinno applications.

Northern Michigan University, Associates in Industrial Power Tech *Marquette, Michigan, Graduated:* 01/2014

2 year program focused on industrial substation, switch yards, energy distribution and relay mechanics.